DAVID CRAWFORD

Houston, TX 77024 (281) 660-2249 david.crawford1995@gmail.com

Skilled technical writer with four years of experience writing medical protocols, training materials, and website content. Expertise in requirement analysis and communication while ensuring proper documentation is recorded, archived, and updated as needed.

EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

VILLAGEMD - HOUSTON, TEXAS

Technical Writer September 2021 – Present

- Develop documentation, including job aids, medical protocols, and processes.
- Review and edit existing documentation in knowledge management database to maintain accuracy and relevancy.
- Interview subject matter experts (SMEs) to become familiar with processes to document.
- Wrote and launched a new knowledgebase in SharePoint that received an 85% satisfaction rating from users.
- Increased agent and provider engagement with knowledge database by 258%.
- Increased viewership of knowledge database and job aids by 290% since the implementation of new website.
- Led a team of executives and national directors to plan and execute medical protocol changes at the call center and clinic levels.

FREELANCE - REMOTE

Writer, Editor June 2020 – Present

- Delivered writing, editing, and proofreading services to individual and business clients. Ensured exceptional experiences through clear communication, consistent follow-up, and quality service delivery.
- Researched, wrote, and proofread 23 pages of the keyword-rich website content, which immediately boosted the client's company rankings to the second page on Google searches and doubled organic leads from website traffic.
- Edited and rewrote a website and marketing materials for a business, resulting in a 75% increase in web traffic and a 200% increase in leads.

SCORPION MARKETING - VALENCIA, CALIFORNIA

Content Manager

January 2020 - April 2020

- Wrote and edited up to five pieces daily with up to 600 words each, including blog articles, website content, and marketing emails for marketing and SEO specialists, project managers, and individual clients.
- Adhered to diverse tone and style specifications in alignment with project requirements to ensure web pages, blogs, and other marketing writing materials maintained the company's message.
- Built a reputation for creating accurate, grammatically sound content targeting specific audiences.

THE PAISANO - SAN ANTONIO, TEXAS

Assistant Managing Editor

August 2018 – January 2019

- Established a clear voice for the publication by developing and documenting a comprehensive style guide.
- Managed a group of 15 writers and editors who reduced publication errors through meticulous editing to elevate
 journal quality and accuracy.
- Contributed to 50% growth in social media engagement by selecting relevant, compelling journal content.
- Edited up to 12 news features, editorial articles, and opinion pieces weekly to ensure factual, concise, explicit, and grammatically accurate content.
- Earned promotion from copy editor to assistant managing editor for leadership and capabilities.

SAGEBRUSH REVIEW - SAN ANTONIO, TEXAS

Intern

September 2016 - January 2017

- Expanded submissions by writing and launching a compelling email marketing campaign that targeted over 100 new leads at universities nationwide.
- Partnered with cross-functional team of editors, writers, and designers in the development and publication of the University of Texas at San Antonio's literary and art journal.
- Contributed to marketing operations by identifying, researching, and reporting on advertising opportunities.

NVATE -REMOTE

Content Writer

November 2014 - July 2015

- Conceptualized and pitched articles on healthcare, technological, and scientific topics, including sleep and nutrition studies, blue light filtering applications, and eco-friendly appliances.
- Researched, wrote, and edited up to three short- and long-form articles monthly for digital publication.
- Earned recognition for on-time delivery, adaptability, and willingness to accept and implement feedback.

EDUCATION

B.A. in English Literature • Creative Writing • University of Texas at San Antonio

CORE SKILLS & QUALIFICATIONS

SEO Research | Content Writing | GitHub | Proofreading | Editing | Word | Excel | HTML | CSS | MS Teams | Slack |
Product Knowledge | SharePoint | Visio | Confluence | SOPs | SME Collaboration | Outlook | Power Automate |
Automation | Document Design | Adobe Suite | Technical Writing | Blogging | Landing Pages | CMS Tools | Email
Marketing | AP Style | Chicago Style | MLA Style | Style Guide Adherence | Research | Google Analytics | Keyword
Optimization | Organizational Skills | Project Management | Team Collaboration | MS Office Suite | Document
Management | Technical Interviews | WordPress | CSS Camtasia | Web Authoring | Graphic Design | OBS | Technical
Research